{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question":"1. What is the pressure drop per unit length for the given parameters for a laminar packed bed setup? Density = 990 Kg/m3 Superficial velocity = 10m/s DP = 3mm Porosity = 0.14 Viscosity = 2.5×10-5kg/ms",
      "answers": {
        "a": "-15.625Pa/m",
        "b": "-15.625KPa/m",
        "c": "-1.875Pa/m",
        "d": "-1.875KPa/m"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If we have a tube of diameter 30mm and particles of diameter 2mm, the length of the tube is 10cm and the number of pellets is 100. Then what is the porosity?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.45",
        "b": "0.95",
        "c": "0.99",
        "d": "0.65"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. If we have a tube of diameter 30mm and particles of diameter 3mm, the length of the tube is 10cm and the number of pellets is 100. The flow rate is 5cm3/s, then what is the superficial velocity?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "0.5 cm/s",
        "b":"0.45 cm/s",
        "c":"0.7 cm/s",
        "d":"0.8 cm/s"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"c",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"4. What is the relation between superficial velocity and average fluid velocity in a packed bed? Where ϑ is the porosity of the bed, φ is the superficial velocity and u is the average velocity",
      "answers":{
        "a":"ϑ=φu",
        "b":"ϑ=u/φ",
        "c":"ϑ=φ0.14u",
        "d":"ϑ=φϑ/uu"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"5. In the Formula for porosity, what is the meaning of the term V? ∅ = V/VT",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Voumne of Void",
        "b":"Volume of Pure Solid",
        "c":"Total Volume",
        "d":"Volume of the tube material"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"6. Which one of the following is the correct expression for Friction Factor in Packed Bed Columns?",
      "answers":{
        "a":"f = 150/Re",
        "b":"f = 150/Re+1.75",
        "c":"f = 180/Re+1.5",
        "d":"f = 100/Re+0.0035"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"7. Calculate the pressure drop in the following setup. Density = 990 Kg/m3 Superficial velocity = 10m/s DP = 3mm Porosity = 0.14 Viscosity = 2.5×10-5 kg/ms Column length = 1m",
      "answers":{
        "a":"7 Pa",
        "b":"724x10^6 Pa",
        "c":"7x10^6 Pa",
        "d":"72 atm"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"8. A fully packed bed with small particle size has _________ pressure drop than a bed with larger particle size",
      "answers":{
        "a":"More",
        "b":"Less",
        "c":"Same",
        "d":"Negligible"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"9. What is the term Ɵ in the Kozeny Carman equation for laminar flow in packed beds? ΔP/L=(−180μ)/(S2D2P) x((1−∈)2/∈3)ϑS",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Surface Area of pellets",
        "b":"Sphericity of Pellets",
        "c":"Void fraction",
        "d":"Density"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"10. Which one of the following is correct expression for sphericity of a particle? Note: Vp = Volume of particle, Ap = Surface areas of the Particle.",
      "answers":{
        "a":"S = (6Vp)/Ap",
        "b":"S = (π1/3(6Vp)2/3)/Ap",
        "c":"S = (π1/3(6Vp)4/3)/Ap",
        "d":"S = (6Vp)2/3/Ap"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    }
  ]
}
